### Research Statement

My research focuses on **democratizing security analysis of AI systems** by improving how people **interpret attacks, quantify vulnerabilities, and protect AI systems from harm**. Through developing a foundational security framework for AI, my work accelerates research innovations and increases education effectiveness by **lowering the barriers to entry for people to learn, design, develop, and test AI techniques**. My research has produced novel defenses that have been tech-transferred to industry. My security framework, becoming available to thousands of students, is transforming AI education at scale.



## Education

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

Ph.D. in Computational Science and Engineering

M.S. in Computational Science and Engineering

Fall 2015 - Spring 2017

Fall 2017 - present

▶ GPA: 3.91/4.0

▶ Advisor: Dr. Polo Chau

▶ Research interests: Adversarial ML, ML security, Explainability and Interpretability in Deep Learning

### Netaji Subhas Institute of Technology, University of Delhi

2010 - 2014

B.E. in Instrumentation and Control Engineering

▶ Thesis: Automatic Speaker Recognition using Student's T-Mixture Model



## Industry Experience

## AWS Lex, Amazon / Applied Scientist Intern

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Developed a novel technique for infusing knowledge graphs in ASR pipeline for improving performance of OOV named entities.

## AWS Transcribe, Amazon / Applied Scientist Intern

May 2020 - Aug 2020

Demonstrated improvement in transcription of accented speech through novel adversarial training paradigm.

#### Alexa Brain, Amazon / Applied Scientist Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Explored generative regularization and implemented several weakly supervised deep learning models for improving name-free skill invocation on the Alexa voice interface.
- Proposed an attention-based, low-rank approximation that learns a shared embedding space for high-level application domains and low-level word tokens.

#### Alexa Al, Amazon / Software Development Engineer Intern

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Developed and evaluated semantic representations in knowledge graphs for improving automatic ontology alignment.

#### Amazon Web Services, Amazon / Web Development Engineer Intern

May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Developed a data pipeline to accelerate the execution time of CloudWatch Logs Search.
- Designed and integrated visualizations in the CloudWatch console to enable quick analysis of AWS metrics.

#### Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi (IIITD) / Research Associate

Sep 2013 - Aug 2015

- Developed from ground-up, a platform for realtime tracking, analysis and visualization of social media data. This is actively being used by several federal and state security agencies in India.
- Developed the TweetCred credibility API and the TweetCred browser extension, which were also covered by popular news outlets including The Washington Post and The New Yorker.

#### Google Summer of Code with ThinkUp / Software Developer Intern

Jun 2013 - Sep 2013

• Developed the data model for analyzing and generating insights from social media data, designed visualizations.

#### mLabs / Software Engineer

Sep 2012 - May 2013

• Developed the complete software and hardware interface for a patented web-enabled electronic prototyping device.

## Honors and Awards

#### # Invited Researcher, Student Immersion Program, Intel Labs

2019

For presentation, discussion and transfer of novel research thrusts

#### Audience Appreciation Award (runner-up) at ACM SIGKDD Conference

2018

For "SHIELD: Fast, Practical Defense and Vaccination for Deep Learning Using JPEG Compression"

#### **\*** KDD Student Travel Award

2018

For participation at the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining

#### # Interspeech Travel Grant

2021

For "Best of Both Worlds: Robust Accented Speech Recognition with Adversarial Transfer Learning"

## Publications

### NeuroCartography: Scalable Automatic Visual Summarization of Concepts in Deep Neural Networks

H. Park, N. Das, R. Duggal, A. P. Wright, O. Shaikh, F. Hohman, D. H. Chau *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (IEEE VIS)*, 2021.

#### Best of Both Worlds: Robust Accented Speech Recognition with Adversarial Transfer Learning

N. Das, S. Bodapati, M. Sunkara, S. Srinivasan, D. H. Chau

Proceedings of the Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association (Interspeech), 2021.

#### SkeletonVis: Interactive Visualization for Understanding Adversarial Attacks on Human Action Recognition Models

H. Park, Z. J. Wang, N. Das, A. S. Paul, P. Perumalla, Z. Zhou, D. H. Chau

Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Demonstration Track (AAAI Demo), 2021.

#### EnergyVis: Interactively Tracking and Exploring Energy Consumption for ML Models

O. Shaikh, J. Saad-Falcon, A. P. Wright, N. Das, S. Freitas, O. Asensio, D. H. Chau

Extended Abstracts of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2021.

#### **GOGGLES: Automatic Image Labeling with Affinity Coding**

N. Das, S. Chaba, R. Wu, S. Gandhi, D. H. Chau, X. Chu

ACM International Conference on Management of Data (SIGMOD), 2020.

#### Bluff: Interactively Deciphering Adversarial Attacks on Deep Neural Networks

N. Das\*, H. Park\*, Z. J. Wang, F. Hohman, R. Firstman, E. Rogers, D. H. Chau *IEEE Visualization Conference (IEEE VIS)*, 2020.

#### Massif: Interactive Interpretation of Adversarial Attacks on Deep Learning

N. Das\*, H. Park\*, Z. J. Wang, F. Hohman, R. Firstman, E. Rogers, D. H. Chau

Extended Abstracts of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2020.

#### **CNN Explainer: Learning Convolutional Neural Networks with Interactive Visualization**

Z. J. Wang, R. Turko, O. Shaikh, H. Park, N. Das, F. Hohman, M. Kahng, D. H. Chau *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (IEEE VIS)*, 2020.

Top of GitHub Trending list, Top 4 TVCG Papers, Invited to ACM SIGGRAPH 21

#### **CNN 101: Interactive Visual Learning for Convolutional Neural Networks**

Z. J. Wang, R. Turko, O. Shaikh, H. Park, N. Das, F. Hohman, M. Kahng, D. H. Chau

Extended Abstracts of ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2020.

#### MLsploit: A Framework for Interactive Experimentation with Adversarial Machine Learning Research

N. Das, S. Li, C. Jeon, J. Jung\*, S. T. Chen\*, C. Yagemann\*, E. Downing\*, H. Park, E. Yang, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, R. Sahita, D. Durham, S. Buck, D. H. Chau, T. Kim, W. Lee KDD Project Showcase, 2019. \* Oral

#### The Efficacy of SHIELD under Different Threat Models

C. Cornelius, N. Das, S. T. Chen, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, D. H. Chau KDD Workshop - Learning and Mining for Cybersecurity (LEMINCS), 2019. \* Oral

#### Visual Analytics for Interpretability on Deep Neural Networks

H. Park, F. Hohman, N. Das, C. Robinson, D. H. Chau NeurlPS Workshop - Women in Machine Learning (WiML), 2019.

#### MLsploit: A Cloud-Based Framework for Adversarial Machine Learning Research

N. Das, S. Li, C. Jeon, J. Jung\*, S. T. Chen\*, C. Yagemann\*, E. Downing\*, H. Park, E. Yang, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, R. Sahita, D. Durham, S. Buck, D. H. Chau, T. Kim, W. Lee Black Hat Asia - Arsenal, 2019.

#### ADAGIO: Interactive Experimentation with Adversarial Attack and Defense for Audio

N. Das, M. Shanbhogue, S. T. Chen, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, D. H. Chau European Conference on Machine Learning & Principles & Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML-PKDD), 2018.

#### SHIELD: Fast, Practical Defense and Vaccination for Deep Learning Using JPEG Compression

N. Das, M. Shanbhogue, S. T. Chen, F. Hohman, S. Li, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, D. H. Chau ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD), 2018. ♣ Audience Appreciation Award (runner-up)

#### Compression to the Rescue: Defending from Adversarial Attacks Across Modalities

N. Das, M. Shanbhogue, S. T. Chen, F. Hohman, S. Li, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, D. H. Chau KDD Project Showcase, 2018.

#### **Defense against Adversarial Attacks using JPEG Compression**

N. Das, M. Shanbhogue, S. T. Chen, F. Hohman, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, D. H. Chau NIPS Workshop - Women in Machine Learning (WiML), 2017.

## Training a Generative Agent Grounded in Cooperative Visual Dialog with Deep Reinforcement Learning

A. Kalia, N. Das, M. Shanbhogue, V. Parthasarathy NIPS Workshop - Women in Machine Learning (WiML), 2017.

### Keeping the Bad Guys Out: Protecting and Vaccinating Deep Learning with JPEG Compression

N. Das, M. Shanbhogue, S. T. Chen, F. Hohman, L. Chen, M. E. Kounavis, D. H. Chau arXiv preprint arXiv:1705.02900, 2017.

#### PASSAGE: A Travel Safety Assistant with Safe Path Recommendations for Pedestrians

M. Garvey, N. Das, J. Su, M. Natraj, B. Verma

ACM International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI), 2016.

## Grants and Funding

#### ★ DARPA Guaranteeing AI Robustness against Deception (GARD) Research Grant

Pl: J. Martin; Co-Pls: C. Cornelius, D. H. Chau; Co-Authors: N. Das, S.T. Chen, S. Freitas; Selected for Award: \$8.1M, 2020 - 2023

#### **★** Amazon AWS Research Grant

Adversarial Re-Training and Model Vaccination for Robust Deep Learning Pl: D. H. Chau; Co-Pls: N. Das, H. Park, S. Freitas; Awarded \$5,000 in AWS cloud credits

#### **★ NVIDIA GPU Grant**

Defending Adversarial Attacks by Robust, Inference-time Local Linear Approximation

Pl: D. H. Chau; Co-Pls: N. Das, S.T. Chen, S. Freitas, F. Hohman; Awarded NVIDIA Titan V GPU worth \$3,000

2018

2019

2018

## Invited Talks and Presentations

#### The Efficacy of SHIELD under Different Threat Models

▶ Intel Labs, Portland, OR, USA (Invited Research Talk, Host: Scott Buck)

Jul 30, 2019

#### Secure and Interpretable Al

▶ Intel Labs, Portland, OR, USA (Invited Research Talk, Host: Li Chen)

Jun 28, 2019

#### **Defending Deep Learning from Adversarial Attacks**

▶ Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA (PhD Qualifier Presentation)

Nov 27, 2018

## Compression to the Rescue: Defending from Adversarial Attacks Across Modalities

▶ Amazon, Seattle, WA, USA (Research Presentation, Host: Y.B. Kim)

May 30, 2018

#### **PASSAGE: A Travel Safety Assistant**

▶ Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA (CSE 6242 Invited Talk, Host: Polo Chau)

Spring & Fall of 2016-2019



## Professional Service

## **Program Committee**

ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, Demo Track (CIKM) 2019, 2020 KDD Workshop on Learning and Mining for Cybersecurity (LEMINCS) 2019

#### Reviewer

European Conference on ML & Principles & Practice of KDD, Demo Track (ECML-PKDD)	2019
ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD)	2019
Deep Learning and Security Workshop at IEEE S&P (DLS)	2018



## Teaching

#### **CSE 6242: Data & Visual Analytics**

• Graduate Teaching Assistant (451 students)

• Head Teaching Assistant (215 students)

• Graduate Teaching Assistant (187 students)

#### Georgia Institute of Technology

Fall 2018

Fall 2016

Spring 2016

## Press

Jun 28, 2019 IC, Georgia Tech. "MLsploit Tackles Machine Learning Security with a Cloud-based Platform"

May 02, 2019 CoC, Georgia Tech. "Demo Day Shows Future of Cybersecurity is Machine Learning"

Jun 01, 2018 CoC, Georgia Tech. "Georgia Tech Teams up with Intel to Protect AI from Malicious Attacks Using SHIELD"

May 05, 2014 The New Yorker. "Can an Algorithm Solve Twitter's Credibility Problem?"

May 02, 2014 The Washington Post. "Lies are everywhere on the Internet. But this free tool could potentially fight them."

May 01, 2014 The Daily Dot. "TweetCred Chrome extension tells you which tweets to trust"



#### GOGGLES: Learning Interpretable Representations of Semantic Concepts [github.com/chu-data-lab/GOGGLES]

Class project for GaTech CS 8803: Data Management for Machine Learning

Fall 2018

• Proposed a novel learning framework that encapsulates high-level semantic concepts as visually grounded prototype embeddings, which serve as labelling functions for inferring class labels for image datasets.

#### Image Segmentation using CRFs and Conditional Image Generation using VAE

Class project for GaTech CS 8803: Probabilistic Graphical Models

Spring 2018

- Experimented with CNNs and CRFs to evaluate DeepLab, a state-of-the-art model in image segmentation.
- Given image segmentation and class labels for the segments, implemented a conditional generative model using VAE.

#### Neuroevolutionary Gait Simulation of Quadruped Robots [bit.ly/cse6730-gait-videos]

Class project for GaTech CSE 6730: Modeling and Simulation

Spring 2016

• Developed a simulation framework wherein quadruped robots were evolved to learn walking gaits through a neuroevolutionary mechanism using a genetic algorithm.

baudcast [github.com/nilakshdas/baudcast]

Independent open-source project

2014

- Developed a socket-based, realtime messaging library for the internet of things paradigm.
- This has been downloaded and used in over 1,000 Node.js projects.

# Technical Skills

Programming: Python, Java, C++, C, Matlab, Scala, SQL

**Big Data:** Apache Storm, Apache Hadoop and MapReduce, Apache Spark, Pig, Apache Lucene **Machine Learning:** TensorFlow, PyTorch, DyNet, Caffe, scikit-learn, Weka, Microsoft Azure ML Studio

Web Development: JavaScript ES7, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, PHP, Django, D3, jQuery



**Dr. Polo Chau**, Associate Professor School of Computational Science and Engineering Georgia Institute of Technology cc.gatech.edu/~dchau/

**Dr. Xu Chu**, Assistant Professor School of Computer Science Georgia Institute of Technology cc.gatech.edu/~xchu33/

**Dr. Ponnurangam Kumaraguru (PK)**, Associate Professor and Associate Dean of Student Affairs Computer Science and Engineering Department Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi (IIITD) iiitd.ac.in/pk